Ashish Yadav Full Stack Developer 1/12 sp ashram Gwalior(M.P.) +91 7999952510



ashish1982gwl@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Full-stack Developer (Java/Angular4) with over 12-year experience in software development and maintenance. Worked in the telecom Sector and an open source Business Process Management I like continuous learning and increasing my skill set as per the business requirements and utilizes all my knowledge along with strong technical and management skills to achieve project specific and

company goals.

I take a pride in finding technology solutions to the real-world problems and have consistently delivered high quality software solutions on time. I keep abreast of the latest technology developments and have an insatiable drive to innovate.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Over 12 years of experience in Software Development (Java, Angular)

One years of experience in Java Script frameworks, especially Angular

- Solid understanding of server side as well as UI side standards and best practices
- Strong problem-solving ability, interpersonal, communication skills, self-starter with the ability to manager pressure situations
- > Significant experience working directly with business for requirement gathering
- ➤ Skilled at learning any technology/tool quickly
- Love and prefer to work on cutting edge technologies

SKILLS PROFILE

Java J2ee Technologies: Angular 2.0, Typescript, JavaScript, Java, Spring boot,

Hibernate, JPA ,Restful Web services

Databases: My SQL, Oracle

Application Servers: Tomcat

Development Tools: Eclipse, Net Beans

Version Control Software: GIT, SVN
Development Models: Agile (scrum)
Build Automation Tools: Apache Maven

Incident Tracking Tools: JIRA

API Manager : Wso2 Api Manager Load Balancer: Nginx, Apache-d

Other Technology: SSL-configuration, J-meter, Apache-Kafka, Open-Fire,

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Sr.	Organization	Duration	
No.			
1	Pyro Networks Pvt	Mar2006- Jan 2008	
2	Spice Digital Pvt. Ltd.	Jan 2008 - sep2015	
3	Spice Digital Pvt. Ltd.	Jan2016 – till date	

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

9. Umang THE SPAIR OF NEW MODA	Dec 2014 – till date
Solution Architect	Spice Digital Pvt. Ltd.

Eclipse Stardust (Open Source):

Umang is app launched by prime minister at 23rd November in 2017.All governent Departments present in single app like PAN, ORS etc.

Roles and Responsibilities (30% UI side and 70% Server side):

- Write high quality UI side module using Angular, HTML5 and other JavaScript Libraries
- Developed several Angular Directives, filters, services and utilities which are commonly used across application
- Designed and implemented a few crucial Angular based views namely Process and Activity Views, Manage Report Module, Authorization View, Participant Manager View, Browser based Model Design, Simple Modeler, Correspondence View
- Few of the views I developed, were in the form of directives which could be embedded in any other view easily
- Wrote more than 50% Restful web services in the application
- Analyse and improve the specifications provided by client side.
- Support all aspects of the project, including write programs, unit test, fix defects, publishing artefacts using maven and other routine maintenance
- Mentor junior teammates from application as well as technology perspective

- Identify and address existing and potential issues proactively for optimal product performance
- Perform detailed review and analysis of the issues reported by client (or Business Units) and fix them
- Evaluate and estimate new enhancements and major bugs
- Participate in product architecture design discussions
- Suggest enhancements to make the product more user friendly and adept with the state of the art features

Achievements

- Doing the R&D as per the requirement using wso2 as API manager for this project.
- Wso2 is also used to distrusted API traffic and also provide data analytics feature.
- Wso2 is used to manage API life cycle etc.
- Nginx used as load balance, Radix used as caching mechanism.

Team Size: 20

Environment (Technology and tools): Angular 2.x, JavaScript, HTML5, Java/J2EE, Spring boot, Hibernate, Web/REST services, Tomcat, MySQL, GIT, Maven, Radis ,Hazelcast, JIRA and WS02.

8. Campaign Manager	June 2012 – Dec-2014
Team lead	Spice Digital Pvt. ltd.

Campaign manager is the project, through we can campaigning the SMS, IVR and Email.

Feature list :-

- 1) CLI management
- 2) Template based sms campaigning
- 3) Unicode message supporting
- 4) Sms schduling
- 5) Memcache based caching mechanisum
- 6) DND filteration
- 7) Green DND
- 8) OBD & Email template approving
- 9) Different types of reports (Detail ,Summary and archive reports)
- 10) Email templating feature
- 11) Parent, child relation management
- 12) Credit management
- 13) Start, Stop and retry based feature.
- 14) User based smsc switching, supporting TPS based control from GUI.

- 15) Supporting Transaction, Promotional based sms.
- 16) PRI based OBD and channel allacation.

Client: SBI, Videocon, IOCL, ICICI bank

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Write high quality UI and backend designing.
- Support 10000 TPS system
- Mem cache based delivery report
- Design the architect of complete project
- End to end product delivery
- Client interaction and requirement gathering

Team Size: 4

Environment (Technology and tools): Angular 2.x, JavaScript, HTML5, Java/J2EE, Struts2, Hibernate, Web/REST services, Tomcat, MySQL, GIT, Maven.

8. M-Commerce	July 2008 – June 2012
Sr. Developer	Spice digital pvt. Ltd.

It's B2B portal have lots feature like train ticket booking , flight booking ,Mobile recaharge etc . B2B portal is used by more than 3000 agent in all over india to money transfer etc.

Feature list :-

- 1) Train ticket booking
- 2) Getting traing list between two station cached based architecture .
- 3) Fligh booking
- 4) Hotel Booking intrgrated cleartrip api
- 5) DTH and Mobile recharge
- 6) Online Prasad
- 7) Money transfer
- 8) Reporting
- 9) CME based application to transfer money to agent
- 10) Alert based services, if agent account credit fall down threshold limit.
- 11) DR management

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyzed new requirements for the release
- Provided guidance to team members who were new to the framework.
- Developed of business layer components and unit testing
- Developed of J2ee components using Servlets and Jsp
- Performed peer review of developed components of other team members
- Tracked the project plan and execute all the activities as per scheduled timeline
- Highlighted and controlled project risks, tasks allocation etc...

Team Size: 30

Environment (Technology and tools): Jsp and servlet, JavaScript, HTML5, Java/J2EE, Struts2, Hibernate, Web/REST services, Tomcat, MySQL, GIT, Maven.

7. Umang Self-care	September 2015 – July 2017
Team Lead	Spice Digital Pvt. Ltd.

New department(PAN,ORS etc) can onboard through this portal.

Based on category, state and center, adming is assigned to department's app.

Department can manage api desgining, banner ang sevice on/ff through this portal.

Also can look the traffic and can analysis api anlytices.

Feature list:-

- 1) Banner change on the fly in app through portal
- 2) API analytices
- 3) API designing
- 4) User management
- 5) Role Management
- 6) Umang rating and feed back management
- 7) API leaf and end api charts and report
- 8) Department and services based hit
- 9) Bolck and unblock services
- 10) SSO management through wso2

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyzed new requirements from client
- Provided guidance to team members who were new to the framework.

- Developed of business layer components and unit testing
- Angular based front hand designing.
- Performed peer review of developed components of other team members
- Tracked the project plan and execute all the activities as per scheduled timeline

Team Size: 5

Environment (Technology and tools): Spring Boot, JavaScript, HTML5, Java/J2EE, Hibernate, Web/REST services, Tomcat, MySQL, GIT, Maven.

6. UPI	April 2012 – August 2014	
Team Lead	Spice Digital Pvt. Ltd.	

UPI is platform used to transfer the money and get money from agent to spice account And also used to booking IRCTC ticket through cutomer care portal .

Feature list :-

- 1) Payment collect request
- 2) Money transfer request
- 3) Check balance
- 4) Money refund
- 5) Alert based service
- 6) Dual ssl based configration
- 7) Server management
- 8) GUI for payment collect request

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Collecting the requirment from ICICI bank partner.
- Server management and ssl configuration
- Code development for api integration with partner.
- Team mentoring
- Intgration with other project through webservice and server to server call

Team Size: 2

Environment: Core Java, J2EE, struts2, mysql, Linux, ssl configuration

5. Vodafone Bot	June 2016 – Jan 2017	
Team lead	Spice Digital Pvt. Ltd.	

Bot system is used to auto response for customercare chat .

Feature list:-

- 1) Facebook intgration
- 2) Used KORE platform to making bot
- 3) Flow management
- 4) Intent understaning
- 5) NLTK intgration.
- 6) Entity based flow
- 7) Synonum based configuration
- 8) Script based coding for bot
- 9) Web hook intgration
- 10) JWT based authentication
- 11) AI support

Roles and Responsibilities:

• Understanding of KORE platform and givning training To team member to develop the bot.

Team Size: 5

Environment: KORE platform and development

POC in vodafon and airtel.

4. Customer Care CRM and Chat	January 2016 – Dec 2016
Team Lead	Spice Digital Pvt. Ltd.

CRM is used support to customer used in umnag, macommerce project and BBPS bangladesh. CRM is user cce agent for resloving daily problem facing by end customer.

Feature list:-

- 1. Email management
- 2. Cusetomer care chat managment
- 3. Android, IOS and Web chat
- 4. Chat history
- 5. Openfire based XMPP chat integration
- 6. OBD feature
- 7. Wrap Up feature
- 8. Refernce Id based customer problem tracking
- 9. Agent break functionality
- 10. Out bond call feature
- 11. Thirteen language support chat and OBD.
- 12. Ticket forwading to techops and department
- 13. Integration with ticket resolving management
- 14. Report management
- 15. Agent creation and User management
- 16. Live information about chat and OBD currently handling by customer care
- 17. Routing feature based on language.
- 18. Different different ticket, OBD, EMAIL and chat reports.
- 19. Bot integration with chat
- 20. BOT messages and chat session timeout from hazelcast caching mechnisum
- 21. Supported 5000 concurrent chat session
- 22. IVR Que management.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Product Designing and Implemention .
- R&D on Cutomize openfire
- TLS-1.2 and SSL configuration on openfire
- Email management
- Team mentoring
- Development
- Designing inegration api with core system

Team Size: 4

Environment: angular2, spring boot, openfire, support TLS -1.2, SSL configuration mysql, Linux, ssl configuration

3. Vodafone Ussd	January 2008 –till date
Sr. Developer	Spice Digital Pvt. Ltd.

It's Soap based zonal architecture, getting high TPS (5000 TPS system) used to activation data pack, And activation roaming pack and recharge mobile communicated with vodafone IN directly. More than 100 of soap webservices intrgrated with IN.response time is less than 20 ms.

Feature list :-

- 1) Data Pack activation by using USSD
- 2) Roaming Pack activation
- 3) Offers activation
- 4) Cluster and DR architecture.
- 5) 5000 TPS is achived in current architecture

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Web service based devlopment
- Development of J2ee components using Servlets and Jsp
- Maintained the various developed components through the various stages of development
- Provided guidance to new team members

Team Size: 3

Environment: Core Java, JSP , servlet ,SOAP webservice (AXIS) , Tomact ApacheD cluster environment .

2. B2C Recharge Application	March 2008 – December 2009
Jr. Developer	Spice Digital Pvt. Ltd.

B2C platform used for DTH and monile recharge.

Currenly used for internal employee for recharging mobile and DTH recharge. It's wallet based application, User can load the money through payment geteway and Can use for recharge mobile and DTH etc. Also intrgrated in various other Spice porject Like Mcommence etc.

Feature list:-

- 1. Mobile Recharge
- DTH Recharge
- 3. Bill Payment
- 4. Coupan code
- 5. MIS
- 6. History management
- 7. Customer care support

8. Plan management

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Design and development of business layer components in java and classes Development of J2ee components using Servlets and Jsp
- Integration with different –different aggregators
- Coding
- Gathering the requierment and development

Team Size: 7

Environment: struts2, JSP, core Java, mysql, Tomact, Linux, ssl-configuration

1. 139	March 2006 – December 2008	
Jr. Developer	Pyro Networks pvt Ltd	

This project got two times e-governance award by indian gorment.

Train pessenger can get the current burth status of booked tarin ticket by sendign Sms to 139.example (PNR to 139)

Feature list:-

- 1) Get the instant birth status of booked train ticket based on sending PNR message to 139
- 2) Get train List from source to destination
- 3) Seat Availabitily status
- 4) Daily report
- 5) Alarm management TAT based alarm configuration

Roles and Responsibilities:

- API intgration through IRCTC
- Coding
- MIS generation
- Request based and operator summary, detail and archive report for buisness purpose

Team Size: 1

Environment: Core Java, JSP, servlet, Tomact and mysql database.

EDUCATION

Completed the **Bachelors of Engineering in Computers** from Maharana Pratap College of Technology in 2004.

Course	School/College	University	Year	Percentage
B. E. Computer	M.P.C.T college Gwalior(M.P.),India	The RGPV University	June 2000- 2004	63.00%
H.S.C. (XII)	Miss Hill School Gwalior(M.P.),India	Madhya Pradesh Board	March 1999	75.20%
S.S.C. (X)	Miss Hill School Gwalior(M.P.),India	Madhya Pradesh Board	March 1997	66.4%

PERSONAL DATA

1/12 Shabd Pratap Ashram Gwalior (M.P.)-474012